<doc>
  <page p="1" label="1">STIRE Photobook
January 2021
November 2020. Balseskin. Landscape photo. Photo by: Cynthia</page>
  <page p="2" label="2"/>
  <page p="3" label="3">IMPRESSUM
EDITOR
Development Perspectives, 10 North Quay,
Drogheda, Co . Louth Ireland.
AUTHORS
Maria Acuna Gonzalez
Paul Crewe
graham.kirwan4@gmail.com
DESIGN
Graham Kirwan
PRINT
Damien Jameson, Ashbourne, Co Meath,
Ireland.
This publication was created as part of the STIRE: SUPPORTING THE
INTEGRATION OF THE RESETTLED project. The project is funded by the Fund for
Asylum, Migration and Integration of the European Union. The content of this
publication represents only the views of the author and is the sole responsibility of
the author. The European Commission is not responsible for the use made of the
information contained therein.</page>
  <page p="4" label="4">WE LOVE WHAT WE DO
BECAUSE WE ARE PASSIONATE
ABOUT IT.
November 2020. Balseskin. Still life photo. Photo by: Cynthia</page>
  <page p="5" label="5">PHOTO 1. March 2020. Castlebar. ‘’This place reminded me of the narrow
houses back home’’. Photo by: Safwan
PHOTO 2. November 2020. Balseskin Self Portrait. Photo by: Cynthia
‘’PHOTOGRAPHY IS A
REALITY SO SUBTLE
THAT IT BECOMES
MORE REAL THAN
REALITY’’
- ALFRED STIEGLITZ</page>
  <page p="6" label="6">PART 1
The photos included in this publication were captured
by participants of STIRE programme’s Photography
Workshop. The participants are refugees and
migrants living in Ireland. They all decided to capture
different moments in order to highlight their unique
experiences. Based on the premise that photography
can be seen as a tool for emancipation, the
productions portrayed in this resource aim to reflect
the experience of settling in a new country.
Development Perspectives would like to invite anyone
accessing this resource to appreciate the stories and
messages behind the pictures.</page>
  <page p="7" label="7">PHOTO. November 2020. Dublin. ‘’One city to another’’. Photo by Prerna</page>
  <page p="8" label="8">‘’GIFTS ARE SOMETHING I HOLD
DEARLY, I RECEIVED THIS FROM A
FRIEND WITH HIS NAME ON IT”
PHOTO. March 2020. Castlebar. Stll Life. Photo by Mohammed</page>
  <page p="9" label="9">‘’I WAS GIFTED EACH OF THESE
FROM MY FRIENDS ALL OF
DIFFERENT FAITHS”
PHOTO. March 2020. Castlebar. Photo by Safwan
PHOTO. March 2020. Castlebar. ‘Stll Life. Photo by Souad
‘’THIS NECKLACE WAS GIFTED TO ME BY A
FRIEND BEFORE WE LEFT. IT HAS QUOTES
FROM THE QURAN FOR PROTECTION”</page>
  <page p="10" label="10">PHOTO. November 2020. Carrickmacross. Stll Life. Photo by Flutura</page>
  <page p="11" label="11">PART 2
In this section, you will find different ideas of
educational activities that can be implemented with
the pictures included in section one of this resource.
We invite anyone implementing the following
activities to reflect on each unique perspective, share
this with others, and learn of how we all see the world
differently.
PHOTO. March 2020. “It’s a change, but we are slowly getting used to it”. Photo by Mohammed</page>
  <page p="12" label="12">ACTIVITIES</page>
  <page p="13" label="13">USING PHOTOGRAPHY
AS A STIMULUS
1.
Photographs can be used in a variety of ways but especially as a stimulus to creative thinking,
discussion and debate. They are an excellent stimulus because they can stimulate individuals,
small or larger groups and photographs can be used to encourage people to talk, explore, compare,
debate, discuss and apply ideas and understandings. They can be used to explore how images are
constructed, what choices and issues face photographers, how images can ‘lie’ or provide ‘partial’
understanding of, and access to issues. Some questions to consider:
• What do I see and think?
• What do I see in an image?
• What key ideas or key words does the image suggest to me?
• What might the people in the image be thinking?
• How do I interpret the image?
• What does it make me think/feel?
• How do others see the same image?
• What do they see?
• What similarities or differences do they see in the image(s)?
• Are our reactions different?
• How would others from different places see the same images?</page>
  <page p="14" label="14">“IRELAND WILL HELP
TO FORGET ABOUT THE
PAIN THAT WE HAVE BEEN
THROUGH”
PHOTO. March 2020. Castlebar. Self portrait. Photo by Maryam</page>
  <page p="15" label="15">SELECTING
2.
Invite the group to look carefully at the whole set of photos. Each individual or pair should pick one or
two photos which they find particularly interesting or which raise important questions or issues for
them.
Participants then form small groups (of for example 4 or 6) and explain their choice to each other.
Each small group then selects one or two photos from the group and explains their choice to the
larger group. Each group does this in turn.
This activity can be used to make a list of issues or questions that might need further study and
discussion.</page>
  <page p="16" label="16">PHOTO. March 2020. Castlebar. “This used to be my business phone. I found myself packing it and had no idea why”. Photo by Mohammed</page>
  <page p="17" label="17">DESCRIBING &amp; NAMING
3.
Divide the group into pairs and invite each pair to choose one photo and to then describe, in their
own words, what is happening in the photo.
Invite them to choose some keywords which best describe the photo (e.g. happy, sad, busy, singing,
speaking, women, poverty, relaxed, hard-working etc.)
Each pair can then share their description and keywords with the whole group.
A list of group keywords can then be compiled and discussed:
• Are there words in common?
• Are the words largely positive or negative or a mixture of both?
• What was the basis for the choices made?
• Does anyone disagree with the labels chosen?
• What evidence is there in the photos for the labels?
• Is there agreement or disagreement as to what might be happening in the photos?
Alternatively, each pair or group can display their photo on a piece of poster paper on the wall with
a set of keywords describing the photo on stickers added to the poster. In this way, the entire set of
photos can be displayed and described.
Invite the whole group to look at all the posters and share agreements or disagreements on the
words chosen to describe particular photos.
The overall list of keywords could be used to initiate a discussion on our images of development or
rights etc.</page>
  <page p="18" label="18">PHOTO. March 2020. Castlebar. Photo by Sohad
“THIS QUARAN IS THE ONE THING I BROUGHT
WITH ME FROM BACK HOME. MY FAITH IS
SOMETHING THAT I HOLD ON TO AND WANT TO
BE ABLE TO GIVE TO MY KIDS“</page>
  <page p="19" label="19">STORYTELLING
4.
Each group or pair can be invited to choose a photo and to then describe what might be happening in
the picture through a story – this could include what happened before the photo was taken and what
might happen afterwards. This activity is designed to encourage more detailed engagement with the
issues etc.</page>
  <page p="20" label="20">PHOTO. March 2020. Castlebar. “I carry my keys to my Syria home wherever I go. It gives me the hope that it’s still there“.</page>
  <page p="21" label="21">QUESTIONING
5.
Give each group or pair a photograph – this could then be mounted on a larger piece of poster paper
so that they can write around the edges. If this is not possible, the questions can be written on a
separate piece of paper.
Invite them to write as many questions as they can about the photo. Questions can be directly
relevant to the photo or to issues raised by the photo. Encourage the group to ask questions that
raise broader issues and challenges.
The questioning process around each photo can then be displayed and shared with the larger group.</page>
  <page p="22" label="22"/>
</doc>